Heiko Oberman Papers 1949-2016 (bulk 1985-2001)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Heiko Oberman Papers 1949-2016 (bulk 1985-2001)
MS 576
Oberman, Heiko Augustinus
The Heiko Oberman Papers comprised the personal and professional papers of Professor Dr. Heiko A. Oberman, a historian and theologian specializing in late Middle Ages and Reformation studies. The bulk of the material is correspondence and academic project files related to his professional life, and records related to his position as Director of the Center for Late Medieval and Reformation Studies, which he founded, at the University of Arizona.
29 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Biographical Note
Heiko Augustinus Oberman (1930-2001) was an acclaimed scholar and educator who made significant contributions to the study of the Reformation and late Medieval and Renaissance history. He was Regents Professor at the University of Arizona and recipient of the Heineken Prize for History in 1996, the highest award for the field.
Oberman was born in the city of Utrecht, the Netherlands on October 15, 1930. He graduated with a doctoral degree in Historical Theology from the University of Utrecht in 1957. He then joined the faculty at the Harvard Divinity School in Church History in 1958, where he was promoted quickly to full professor in 1963 and held the Winn Professor of Ecclesiastical History. Oberman left Harvard in 1966 for the University of Tübingen, in Germany where he was a chair in the Theology Department and later Director of the Institute for Late Middle Ages and Reformation Research. He was also an observer at the four sessions of the Second Vatican Council (Vatican II), 1962-1965.
In 1984 Oberman joined the History department at the University of Arizona and founded the Center for Late Medieval and Reformation Studies. Amongst his many accomplishments was launching the annual Town and Gown and Summer Lecture Series which drew upon Oberman's extensive network of colleagues and brought many of Europe and North America's leading scholars to Tucson.
Professor Oberman is a Fellow of the Medieval Academy of America, and Corresponding fellow of the British Academy of Arts and Sciences. He has received honorary degrees from Harvard University, the University of St. Louis and the University of Aberdeen, Scotland. In 1991 he was chosen as a member of the American Philosophical Society. He was author or editor of thirty books and some hundred articles. Oberman is particularly known for his prize-winning study The Harvest of Medieval Theology (Harvard University Press, 1963) and for his Luther: Man Between God and the Devil (English version, Yale University Press, 1982), for which he received the German Historischer Sachbuchpreis for "the most significant history book during the decade 1975-1985." Coincident with the diagnosis of his terminal illness, it was announced that a distinction for extraordinary representation of Dutch scholarship and culture would be conferred on Heiko Oberman by Queen Beatrix of the Netherlands in April 2002.
Heiko Oberman passed away on April 22, 2001 from melanoma. In 2010 Oberman’s extensive personal library was transferred to the University of Arizona Libraries. The collection, nearly 10,000 volumes, centers on the late Middle Ages, the Renaissance, and the Reformation.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into ten series
Series I: Correspondence, 1983-2006
Sub-Series 1: General A-Z, 1984-2001
Sub-Series 2: Brill Files, correspondence as Editor in Chief of 2 journals, 1984-2000
Sub-Series 3: Correspondence with Publishers, 1983-2006
Sub-Series 4: Project Correspondence, 1985-2003
Series II: Travel Files, Lectures and Events, 1964-2000
Sub-Series 1: Travel Files, 1964-2000
Sub-Series 2: Lectures, Events and Sermons, 1973-2000
Sub-Series 3: University of Arizona and Tucson Events, 1986-2000
Series III: Teaching Materials, circa 1950-1998
Series IV: Organization files, 1977-2004
Series V: Project Files, 1958-2008
Sub-Series 1: Book and Article Reviews, 1958-2001
Sub-Series 2: Book Purchases and Inventory, 1981-1998
Sub-Series 3: Manuscripts and Project Files, 1970-2008
Series VI: Vatican II Materials, 1958-1979
Series VII: Personal Files, Family and Colleague Correspondence, 1950-2016
Sub-Series 1: Journals, personal notes, 1950-1954
Sub-Series 2: Personal Files (home office) and Family Correspondence, 1949-2016
Sub-Series 3: Thomas A. Brady, Jr. Correspondence, 1971-2003
Series VIII: Publications, 1958-2005
Series IX: Media (floppies, CDs), circa 1980-2000
Series X: Audio Visual Materials, circa 1960-2000
Scope and Content Note
The Oberman Papers are predominately a correspondence collection related to a number of areas of his professional life including teaching, lecturing, preaching, extensive travels, his academic publishing and editorial work, and service with a variety of organizations. The collection ncludes information about projects, colleagues and academic affairs at Harvard University, the University of Tubingen and the University of Arizona. The materials are largely in the English language, but twenty percent of the collection, especially records earlier than 1985, are in German and Dutch.
Other formats include publications, ephemera, journals, media, and photographs. Some newspaper clippings and pamphlets are embedded with correspondence, publications, travel and project files and there are clippings collected topically including reviews of Oberman’s publications and publicity for events, awards, and news items. There is a small series of photographs that are reproductions of illustrations used in Oberman’s book Luther: Man Between God and the Devil and clippings. There are a number of audio recordings including lectures and notes on cassettes, microcassettes and reel to reel. There are also digital files on floppy disks (3 ½ and 5 ¼) and CD’s. The collection includes copies of Oberman’s publications, offprints, and a limited amount of publications from other authors.
The collection also includes correspondence related to Oberman collected by colleagues, especially Thomas A. Brady, Jr., of Stanford University, family members and friends, especially covering the years 2001-2005 following Oberman’s illness and death.
Bloom Southwest Jewish Archives audio tapes collection, 1980s-1990s
Oberman, Heiko Augustinus.; Martin, Luther.; Calvin, John.; Brady, Thomas A., Jr..; University of Arizona.; Harvard University.; Universität Tübingen.; History--Religious aspects--Christianity.; Religious education--Study and teaching.; Reformation.; Christianity and Judaism.; Anti-clericalism.; Anti-Semitism.; Church history.; Augustinians.; Tucson--Arizona--United States.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1983-2006; Series I
  - General A-Z, 1984-2001; Subseries 1
    The General correspondence series is largely professional and work related, but some family and personal correspondence is mixed in. In many cases a copy of an outgoing response is affixed to the incoming letter. Below the alpha category are date ranges, for example for “B” correspondence folders are divided: 1984-1986, 1986-1991, 1991-1993, 1993-1995, and 1996-2001, these date ranges correspond to the original order of HAO’s files. Folders are organized as working files with the most recent material in the front.
    - A, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - A, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - A, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - B, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - B, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - B, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - B, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - B, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - B, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - B (continued), 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - B, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - B (continued), 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - B (continued), 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - B (continued), 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - C, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - C, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - C, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - C, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - C, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - D, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - D, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - D, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - D, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - D, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - E, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - E, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - E, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - E, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - E, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - F, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - F, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - F, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - F, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - F, 1996-2001 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - G, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - G, 1986-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - G, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - G, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - G (continued), 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - G, 1995-2002 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - H, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - H, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - H, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - H, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - H, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - H, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - H, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - H, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - I-J, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - I-J, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - I-J, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - I-J, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - I-J, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - K, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - K, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - K, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - K, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - K (continued), 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - K, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - K (continued), 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - L, 1964, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - L, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - L, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - L, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - M, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - M, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - M, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - M, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - M (continued), 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - M, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - M, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - M, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - N, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - N, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - N, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - N, 1995-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - O, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - O, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - O, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - O, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - O, 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - P-Q, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - P-Q, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - P-Q, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - P-Q, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - P-Q, 1996-2001 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - P-Q (continued), 1996-2001 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - R, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - R, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - R, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - R, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - R, 1995-2001 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - S, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - S, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - S, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - S (continued), 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - S, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - S, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - S, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - S (continued), 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - S, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - S (continued), 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - S, 1996-2001 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - T, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - T, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - T, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - T, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - T, 1995-2001 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - U-V, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - U-V, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - U-V, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - U-V, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - U-V, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - W, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - W, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - W, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - W, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - W, 1996-2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - X-Y-Z, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - X-Y-Z, 1986-1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - X-Y-Z, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - X-Y-Z, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - X-Y-Z, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Brill Files, correspondence as Editor in Chief of 2 journals, 1984-2000; Subseries 2
    Includes correspondence with publishers, editors and authors and includes manuscripts and reviews with facsimiles of outgoing correspondence attached. Organized alphabetically and chronologically. Oberman was the editor-in-chief of Studies in Medieval and Reformation Thought and Studies in the History of Christian Thought.
    - General Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - General Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Published authors, A-B, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Published authors, C, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Published authors, D-G, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Published authors, H-K, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Published authors, L, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Published authors, M-O, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Published authors, P-Q, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Published authors, R, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Published authors, S, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Published authors, S (continued), 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Published authors, T-Z, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Catalogs and book order forms, 1987-2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Publish or Perish Symposium, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence with Publishers, 1983-2006; Subseries 3
    Project correspondence concerning the publication of HAO’s work, translation, rights and permissions and requests for reviews. Also includes administrative correspondence, financial and logistical information. Organized alphabetically by publishing house.
    - Baker House, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bohlau Verlag, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Brill, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Christianity Today, undated, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cornell University Press, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Crossroad/Continuum, 1985, 1988, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Doubleday, 1991-1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Eerdmans, 1991-2005 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fortress Press, 1984-2004 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Garland, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - de Gruyter, 1987-2001 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Harvard University Press, 1986-2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Instituto Italiano per gli Studi Filosofici, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - J. C. B. Mohr, Submissions, Contributions to the History of Biblical Exegesis (BGBE), 1992-1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - J. C. B. Mohr, Contributions to the History of Biblical Exegesis (BGBE), 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - J. C. B. Mohr, Paul Siebeck, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Labyrinth Press, 1985-1990 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Newsweek, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - North Carolina Press, 1983, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - NRC Handelsblad, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Oxford University Press, 1994, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Past and Present, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Princeton University Press, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Quell Verlag, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Siedler, Sternstunden der Christenheit, Europe’s De-Christianization, 1987-2001 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Siedler Verlag, 1992-2001 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Siedler Verlag, 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Sigler Press, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Sixteenth Century Journal, 1988-2000 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge (SPCK), 1986-1993 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Theologischer Verlag und Buchhandlungen (TVZ), 2000 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 1984-1990 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Ton Bolland (Amsterdam), 1986-1996 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - T & T Clark, 1985-1993 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - T & T Clark, Naples, 4 summer lectures, La Teologia della Riforma, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Vitgeversmaatschappij, J. H. Kok B. V., 1990 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - University of Arizona Press, 1985-1989 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - University of Michigan Press, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Vandenhoeck & Ruprecht, 1984-1989 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Variorum (Gower House Pub.), 1984-1991 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - VG Wort, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Westminster John Knox Press, 1991, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Yale University Press, 1985-2006 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Project Correspondence, 1985-2003; Subseries 4
    Correspondence related to collaborative efforts, manuscripts, events, publications, conferences, and Festschrifts and Oberman’s major research projects. Organized alphabetically by project.
    - Abington Press, Reformation textbook, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Cornelius Augustijn article, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bakhuizen van den Brink, library introduction, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Brothers and Sisters of the New Devotion, preface, Paulist Press, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Martin Bucer, essay, D. F. Wright, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Knowledge of God with Calvin and Barth, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - John Calvin: The Mystery of his Impact, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Calvin et ses Contemporains, Paris conference, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Cape, Reformation textbook, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Casa Eranos, Augustine and Luther, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Classics of Western Spirituality Series, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Contra Vanum, Roots and Ramifications, T & T Clark, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - The Dawn of the Reformation, 2nd ed., 1987-1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Die Reformation, Italian, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Graf Dohna, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Festschrift, Martin Greschat, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Festschrift, Marion Kobelt-Goertz, 1993-1996 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Festschrift, Kenneth Hagen, ed. Maschke, 1988-2001 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Festschrift, Kenneth Hagen, ed. Maschke, (continued), 1988-2001 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Festschrift, Josef Macek, Frantisek Smahel, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Festschrift, Erich Meuthen, 1992-1994 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Festschrift, Hans-Christoph Rublack, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Festschrift, Van ‘t Spijker, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Festschrift, Lou H. Silberman, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Festschrift, David Steinmetz, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Festschrift, Gerald Strauss, 1989-1992 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Festschrift, Charles Trinkaus, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Festschrift, Sir Elton Geoffrey, MacMillian, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Festschrift, George Williams, 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Festschrift, George Williams, (continued), 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Foedus, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Gansfort translation project, Victoria Speder, 1997-1999 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Gettysburg Address, Luther and the Devil, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Groot Goudriaan, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Hammer speech, Berndt Hamm, 1993, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Heineken lecture, The Devil and Devious Historian, Amsterdam, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Historisches Kolleg, The Long Fifteenth Century, Brady, Munich Colloquium, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Philip C. Holtrop, preface, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Hus paper, Beyreuth, Germany, 1993-1998 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Kerk en Theologie, Dutch Sermon, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Hans-Walter Krumwiede project, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Ignatius of Loyola, Bilbao, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Kerk & Theologie, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Kok Kampen, 1982-1988 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Kok Kampen, the Heartland of John Calvin, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Kok Kampen, Luther (Dutch), 1988 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Kok Kampen, Kutte und Kultur, 1990-2001 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Kok Kampen, Kutte und Kultur, (continued), 1990-2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Kok Kampen, Sternstunden, 1984-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Kok Kampen, Reuchlin translation, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Kutte und Kulture, Alexander Fest Verlag, 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Laterza, Milan, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Laterza, Naples lectures, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Luther paperbacks, DTV, Siedler, Laterza, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Luther and the Via Moderna, Trent lecture, 2000-2003 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Luther and the Via Moderna, Trent lectures, continued), 2000-2003 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Luther and the Via Moderna, Trent lectures, (continued), 2000-2003 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Masters of the Reformation, preface, Trinity Press, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Neukirchener, 1995-2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Neukirchener, Texte series, 1991-1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Neukirchener, Quellen, 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Neukirchener, Grundtexte (sequel to Quellen), 1985-2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Neukirchener, new series, 1985-2001 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Oxford University Press, John Buchard, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - The Reformation, Roots and Ramifications, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - The Reformation, Roots and Ramifications, Vol. 2, 1988-1994 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Reuchlin project, Stefan Rhein, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Reuchlin and the Jews, Pforzheimer, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Scholder Symposium, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - SPCK, Reformation textbook (English version of Quellen), 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Paltz III, Spatmittelalter un Reformation (SuR), Christoph Burger, Dohna, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Spatmittelalter un Reformation Neue Reihe (SuR NR), J. C. B. Mohr and ed. Dr. Hans Christoph Stoodt, 1991, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Spatmittelalter un Reformation Neue Reihe (SuR NR), published, 1994-1999 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Spatmittelalter un Reformation Neue Reihe (SuR NR), general correspondence, 1991-1999 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Spatmittelalter un Reformation Neue Reihe (SuR NR), submissions, 1991-2000 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Spatmittelalter un Reformation Neue Reihe (SuR NR), submissions, 1991-2000 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Teufelsdreck, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Tolerance and Intolerance, Cambridge, England, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Via Calvini, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Paul Vignaux, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Wessell Gansfort: Magister Contradictions, 1990-1994 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Yale Intellectual Series, Browsma, 1991-1996 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Travel Files, Lectures and Events, 1964-2000; Series II
  - Travel Files, 1964-2000; Subseries 1
    Folders labeled by destination city and organized chronologically, includes correspondence, conference or event information, receipts and financial information. Organized chronologically.
    - Travel files, 1964-1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Via Antiqua and Via Moderna, AHA, Chicago, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - German-American Interrelations, Maryland-Tübingen Symposium, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Christianity and the Renaissance, Florida and Italy, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Luther lecture, Parker Perry, Albuquerque, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Macalester College, St. Paul, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Book Award, Dusseldorf, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Sixteenth Century Studies Conference, Columbus, OH, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 14)